<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--<?xml-model href="tei_xinclude.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>-->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="xinclude" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title><term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/> Help</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Author</resp>
               <persName xml:id="bwb" ref="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7217-9167">Benjamin W. Bohl</persName>
               <persName xml:id="dr" ref="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6271-2095">Daniel Röwenstrunk</persName>
               <persName xml:id="kh" ref="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-2915-353X">Kristin Herold</persName>
            </respStmt>         
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher ref="www.edirom.des">Virtueller Forschungsverbund Edirom</publisher>
            <availability>
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0)</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Written in Open Office by Edirom Project (DFG) https://edirom.de/edirom-projekt/. Converted to TEI P5 using oxgarage, see <ptr target="#change_1"/></p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-03-25" who="#bwb">
            <list>
               <item>Moved tei:head/@xml:id to parent tei:div using headId2parentDivId.xquery; removed leading line breaks in tei:head elements; rephrased "installation" and inserted tei:note[@type='editorial'] on insertion of installation information; changed old corresponding parts on installation into xml comments; wrapped 'Installation' and 'Application Startup' with 'Preparation' div; removed 'id_' from all @xml:id; rephrased 'Application Startup'; comletely reworkeg 'GUI' chapter; inserted TODO comments;</item>
               <item>Updated Ids and Anchors using scripts/anchorId2parentId.xquery; deleted empty lines; deleted back-to-top links; changed tei:graphic/@src to point to original pix of Edirom Viewer Help;created first help_en.pdf using standard oXygen tranformation scenario for TEI P5 to PDF;</item>
               <item>Updated document name to "Edirom Online Help"; inserted me as author with xml:id for change references; changed pubStmt to unpublished; removed leading '../../0119a239-cd85-4b1a-9a15-abf5ffea2131/' from every tei:graphic/@url; introduce4d tei:body/tei:head;</item>
               <item xml:id="change_1">Converted from HTML version to TEI P5 using oxgarage web sercice</item>
            </list>
         </change>
         <change from="2013-04-02" to="2013-04-03" who="#bwb" xml:id="change_4">reworked text from "toolbar" onwards; created separate chapters for <ptr target="#toolbar_top"/> and <ptr target="#help_view.desktop.TaskBar"/>; added description for the buttons in help_view.desktop.TaskBar; reworked chapter on windows; inserted passages on views;</change>
         <change when="2013-07-03" who="#bwb">updated occurrences of "Edirom Online" to <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/></change>
         <change when="2013-07-11" who="#bwb" xml:id="change_6">reworked preferences description; made preferences description a comment due to implementation status</change>
         <change when="2013-07-22" who="#bwb"> deleted comment with manually edited TOC; provided description of annotation-view; deleted description of annotations window; reworked chapter on annotations; made all ediromGui terms empty elements; removed some generated xml:id attributes;</change>
         <change when="2013-07-30" who="#bwb">overhauled structure of button entries; corrected some typos; added missing button descriptions in annotation-view;</change>
         <change when="2013-08-01" who="#bwb">
            <list>
               <item>removed tei:q around some terms as terms now with css class .term; added TODO comments searchView and preferences;</item>
               <item>removed generated IDs from conversion to TEI P5; where applicable, inserted tei:head in tei:figure; overhauled priority images to match new figure-structure; prettified XML indentation; wrapped annotation categories table with figure; added description of Annotation View's TaskBar Buttons; added TaskBar screenshot; corrected figure head of Tool Bar; changed ID from toolbar_bottom to help_view.desktop.TaskBar; added description of annotationOverview.png; added TODO comments; matched EdiromHelp SVN and GitHub; added workspace-switcher.png;</item>
            </list>
         </change>
         <change when="2013-08-07" who="#bwb">corrected long lang_vars in pull request;</change>
         <change when="2013-08-08" who="#bwb">added description of searchWindow; deactivated link to missing preferences section;</change>
         <change when="2024-12-05" who="#kh">update metadata (add orcid, delete old addresses etc.)</change>
         <change when="2024-12-10" who="#kh">replaced old (partly deprecated) content with updated and revised german help, which was translated to english; correct indentation</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
     <front>
       <titlePage>
         <titlePart>Help (User Manual)</titlePart>
         <argument>
            <p>This document contains a general introduction to the use of <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/>. It describes the basic functions of the software. Not all of the options described below may be available in every edition, as content is created on a project-specific basis and each edition is subject to its own individual edition guidelines.
               Furthermore, for edition-specific reasons, it is possible that some versions contain extensions that are not listed and explained in this document.
            </p>
         </argument>
       </titlePage>
       <pb/>
       <divGen type="toc"/>
     </front>
        <body>
         <!-- USER INTERFACE -->
            <div type="div1" xml:id="gui">
               <head>User interface</head>
               <p>The application interface of <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/> consists of different areas. At the top is the <ptr target="#toolbar_top"/>, at the bottom is the <ptr target="#taskbar"/>. 
                  The area in between is the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/>, within which all internal application windows are opened to display the content of an edition and gain access to additional functions. On the right is the <ptr target="#navigator"/>
               </p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/fullscreen_en.png"/>
                  <head>An example view of the <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/> window, which shows the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar"/> (top), the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar"/> (bottom), the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/> and the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/> (right).</head>
               </figure>
               
            <!-- user interface TOOLBAR -->
               <div type="div2" xml:id="toolbar_top">
                  <head>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar"/>
                  </head>
                  <p>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_home"/> is located on the left edge of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar"/>.
                      Next to it is the <term type="ediromGui" key="comboBox"/>. This enables a selection of the various works contained within an edition and thus attempts to emulate the structure of a “classic” printed edition volume with several works included.
                      The <term type="ediromGui" key="comboBox"/> and thus the packaging of several works in one edition (analogous to an earlier edition volume) is used less frequently in newer <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/> versions and the name of the individual work edition appears in its place.
                      On the right is the input for the <ptr target="#search"/> and a button that opens an <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_about"/> window.
                   </p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/menubar_en.png"/>
                     <head>Detailed view of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar"/> with <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar_homeBtn"/> and <term type="ediromGui" key="comboBox"/> for the work selection (left) and the search field (right).</head>
                  </figure>
                  <div type="div3" xml:id="search">
                     <head>
                        <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.search.SearchWindow_Title"/>
                     </head>
                     <p>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_search"/> window can be opened by clicking the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_search"/> button (magnifying glass) in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar"/> or by entering a search query in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar_searchField"/>.
                        A text-based search is performed on all content in the edition.</p>
                     <figure>
                        <graphic url="help/images/searchField.png"/>
                        <head>Detailed view of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TopBar_searchField"/>: Clicking on the magnifying glass triggers the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_searchWin"/> command.</head>
                     </figure>
                     <p>After a search query is executed, all results are grouped with corresponding content, eg text document, annotation.
                        Individual search results may be highlighted separately.
                        If a search query results in more than three hits per entry, a <q>Show all hits</q> link appears.</p>
                     <figure>
                        <graphic url="help/images/searchWindow_en.png"/>
                        <head>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.search.SearchWindow_Title"/> window</head>
                     </figure>
                   </div>
               </div>
               
            <!-- user interface NAVIGATOR (CONTENT OVERVIEW)-->
               <div type="div2" xml:id="navigator">
                  <head>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/>
                  </head>
                  <p>On the right of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/> is the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/>. 
                     The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/> contains an edition-specific list of objects that can be organized into categories. 
                     If an element in the list is clicked, the corresponding object opens in a window of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/>.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/navigator_en.png"/>
                     <head>An exemplary <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>If the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/> contains many objects, you can navigate through the contents using the scroll bar on the right edge of the window.
                     The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/> is fixed to the upper right corner, but can be resized via <term type="ediromGui" key="drag-and-drop"/> at the left or bottom edge.</p>
               </div>
            
            <!-- user interface TASKBAR -->
               <div type="div2" xml:id="taskbar">
                  <head>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar"/>
                  </head>
                  <p>Through the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar"/> at the bottom of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/> the global content-related functions can be accessed on the left and the meta functions on the right.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/taskBar_en.png"/>
                     <head>Detailed view of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>The first three buttons on the left control the different arrangement of all open content windows on the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/>.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/arrangeButtons_grid.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_Sort_grid"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/arrangeButtons_horizontal.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_Sort_horizontal"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/arrangeButtons_vertical.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_Sort_vertical"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>The bars of facsimiles and editions are usually provided with bar numbers; these can be shown and hidden for all open windows with musical content using the fourth button from the left.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/measureNumbers.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_measureNumbers"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>Music editions or facsimiles and libretto editions can contain annotations that can be opened using annotation symbols.
                     With the speech bubble button you can <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_annotations"/>.
                     Annotations can be assigned priorities and categories. Filtering annotations according to these priorities and annotations is not possible via the global button in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar"/>, but only via selection in an individual window.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/annotations.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_annotations"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/> button opens a new <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/> in <term type="ediromGui" key ="global_appName"/>. This will open a completely new set of windows without changing the contents of the current desktop.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/workspace-switcher.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.Desktop"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>Der Button mit den zwei horizontalen Pfeilen löst den Befehl <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_concordanceNav"/> aus und es öffnet sich der Navigator für <ptr target="#concordanceNavigator"/>, Details zur Bedienung des Konkordanz-Navigators finden sich im entsprechenden Abschnitt.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/concordanceNavigator.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_concordanceNav"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <p>At the bottom right, you can use the question mark button to open the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_help"/> or move it to the foreground.</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/help.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_help"/></head>
                  </figure>
               </div>
            </div>
           
         <!-- CONCORDANCE NAVIGATOR -->
            <div type="div1" xml:id="concordanceNavigator">
               <head>
                    <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.concordanceNavigator.ConcordanceNavigator_Title"/>
               </head>
               <p>The navigator for <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.concordanceNavigator.ConcordanceNavigator_Title"/> enables cross-source navigation in all corresponding facsimiles or the edition. 
                  Another example of the application is the concordance of scores and the corresponding verses of a libretto in order to be able to view the musical instructions alongside the specific verse lines at the same time.
                  However, the existence of the concordances in question depends on the respective edition.
                  If the selected concordance contains further subdivisions, such as sentences, a second drop-down menu will appear for selection.</p>
               <figure>
                    <graphic url="help/images/concNav_en.png"/>
                    <graphic url="help/images/concNav2_en.png"/>
                    <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.desktop.TaskBar_concordanceNav"/> with and without additional drop-down menu.</head>
                </figure>
                <p>Below the slider is the button <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.concordanceNavigator.ConcordanceNavigator_Show"/>. 
                  This must be clicked to open the selected measure in all open sources on the desktop.
                  You can also navigate forward or backward at the measure level within the sources using the arrows to the right and left of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.concordanceNavigator.ConcordanceNavigator_Show"/> button.
                  However, if the selected measure occurs in other sources that are not currently open, a button will appear at the bottom right that opens all other sources and rearranges the windows</p>
            </div>

         <!-- CONTENT WINDOWS -->
         <div type="div1" xml:id="windows">
            <head>Content windows</head>
            <p>At the top of a window with content there is a line that shows the title of the open object.
               Under the title bar, each window has a <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/>.
               On the left in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/> is the <term type="ediromGui" key="comboBox"/>, with which you can switch between different <term type="ediromGui" key="views"/> of the currently open window, e.g. <ptr target="#view_text"/>, <ptr target="#facsimileView"/>, <ptr target="#view_XML"/>.
               Depending on the view selected, the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.BottomBar"/> may be displayed at the bottom of the window, which provides different tools for manipulating the various objects.</p>
            
            <!-- content windows TEXT-VIEW -->
            <div type="div2" xml:id="view_text" change="#change_4">
               <head>
                  <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_textView"/>
               </head>
               <p>If the content of a window is text-based, e.g. a TEI file, the entry for <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_textView"/> is within a <term><term type="ediromGui" key= "view.window.TobBar_View"/>Menu</term> window available.
                  The <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_textView"/> appears in a similar form to a web page and may contain links to other content.
               </p>
            </div>
            
            <!-- content windows FAKSIMLE -->
            <div type="div2" xml:id="facsimileView">
               <head>
                  <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_sourceView"/>
               </head>
               <p>If <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_sourceView"/> is one of the possible views of an object, the images from the source are shown.</p>
               <!-- content windows Faksimile TOOLBAR -->
               <div type="div3" xml:id="facsimileView_toolbar">
                  <head>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/>
                  </head>
                  <p>In the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/> there are the following additional menus.</p>
                  <!-- content windows Faksimile toolbar VIEWMENU -->
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="bold">
                        <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_viewMenu"/><lb/>
                     </hi>
                     Under <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.text.TextView_viewMenu"/> there are the following sub-points:
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_showMeasures"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>The option supports the control of the display of measure numbers from the current source.
                           Measure numbers appear in the middle of each measure.</item>
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_fitView"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>The entry controls the adjustment of the zoom level of the source to the current window size.</item>
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_layersMenu"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>The menu entry shows or hides existing layers in the music if they were provided by the edition.
                           These layers could, for example, be colored notes to visually highlight the additions in the autograph or facsimiles.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <!-- content windows Faksimile toolbar ANNOTATIONSMENU -->
                  <p>
                     <hi>
                        <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_annotationsMenu"/><lb/>
                     </hi>
                     Under <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_annotationsMenu"/> there are the following sub-points.
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_ShowAnnotations"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>The option enables the display of the critical report annotations as annotation symbols on the facsimiles or edition.
                           Annotations can be filtered by priority and category (see below).
                           In each source, only the annotations that are related to the open source are displayed.
                           Mouseover over the annotation symbol opens a tooltip that can be used to open the annotation in a new window.</item>
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_prioMenu"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>Option to filter comments by priority.</item>
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_categoriesMenu"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>Option to filter comments by category.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <!-- content windows Faksimile toolbar ANNOTATIONSMENU -->
                  <p>
                     <hi rend="bold">
                        <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_gotoMenu"/><lb/>
                     </hi>
                     The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_gotoMenu"/> has the following functions:
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_gotoMeasure"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>The option opens a dialog in which the desired division and measure number can be entered.</item>
                        <label>
                           <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_gotoMovement"/>
                        </label>
                        <item>Listing of all divisions or edition-specific sections within a source.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <!-- content windows Faksimile TASKBAR -->
               <div type="div3" xml:id="facsimileView_taskbar">
                  <head>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.BottomBar"/>
                  </head>
                  <p>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.BottomBar"/> contains the following tools for navigation within the content of the sources:</p>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/pageView.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_PageBasedView"/>: switches to page-based navigation of the source.</head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/barView.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView"/>: switches to measure-based navigation of the source. When this view is activated, the following three additional tools appear in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.BottomBar"/>.</head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/SourceView_measureBasedCombo.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView"/>, <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_measureBasedCombo"/>: The movement whose measures should be displayed can be selected.</head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/selectVoices.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView"/>, <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView_selectVoices"/>: Individual parts can be selected. This tool is only available when different parts are in the encoding.</head>
                  </figure>  
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/SourceView_measureBasedRange.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView"/>, <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_measureBasedRange"/>: Enter a measure range through which you want to scroll.</head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/slider.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_zoomSlider"/></head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/zoom-fit.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_fitView"/>: resizes the current source to fit the window.</head>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <graphic url="help/images/prev-box-next.png"/>
                     <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_PageBasedView_pageSpinner"/> or <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView_measureSpinner"/></head>
                     <p>The number in the number field shows the current page number (<term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_PageBasedView"/>) or measure number (<term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.source.SourceView_MeasureBasedView "/>).
                        Switching to another page or measure is possible by clicking on the arrow heads or entering a number in the number field.
                        The possible numbers correspond to the source, so they do not always start with 1 and can also contain alphanumeric characters.</p>
                  </figure>
               </div>
            </div>
            
            <!-- content windows XML-VIEW -->
            <div type="div2" xml:id="view_XML">
               <head>
                  <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_xmlView"/>
               </head>
               <p>In the <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_xmlView"/> there are the following options in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/>.</p>
               <list type="gloss">
                  <label>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_decreaseFontSize.label"/>
                  </label>
                  <item><term><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_decreaseFontSize.title"/>-Button</term></item>
                  <label>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_increaseFontSize.label"/>
                  </label>
                  <item><term><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_increaseFontSize.title"/>-Button</term></item>
                  <label>
                     <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_showLineNumbers.label"/>
                  </label>
                  <item><term><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.xmlView_showLineNumbers.title"/>-Button</term></item>
               </list>
            </div>

            <!-- content windows ANNOTATION VIEW -->
            <div type="div2" xml:id="annotationView">
               <head>
                  <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_annotationView"/>
               </head>
               <p>With the sub-item <term type="ediromGui" key="controller.window.Window_annotationView"/> from the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TobBar_View"/> menu you can change the readings or the individual ones Open annotations from the critical report of this work.
                  Some editions also offer an entry to the critical report as a topic in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/>.
                  The header of the critical report can have the following entries.
                  <list type="gloss">
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_No"/></label>
                     <item>Shows the running number of the annotations.</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_TitleLabel"/></label>
                     <item>Title of the annotation, which clarifies the subject of the annotation.</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Categories"/></label>
                     <item>Categories that can be assigned to an annotation.</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Priority"/></label>
                     <item>Priority that can be assigned to an annotation.</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Source"/></label>
                     <item>Source(s) in which the annotation occurs.</item>
                  </list>
               </p><lb/>
               <p>Clicking on a header category rearranges the data in ascending or descending order.
                  An arrow in the right corner of the header when mouse-over opens a context menu with the following setting options:
                  <list type="bulleted">
                     <item>Setting the order.</item>
                     <item>Show/hide individual header entries.</item>
                     <item>Apply a filter to the respective column.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>Double-clicking on an entry in the annotation list opens the detailed view of the annotation.
                  In the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/> under <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Display"/>the associated sources can be arranged as follows.
                  <list type="gloss">
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Grid"/></label>
                     <item>Shows the images from all associated sources in a grid. By double-clicking on an individual object, it can be displayed in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Single"/> (see below).</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Single"/></label>
                     <item>Shows the source snippet to which the annotation refers.
                        With a double click you can go back to the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Grid"/> (see above) or <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_ListView"/> ( see below).</item>
                     <label><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_ListView"/></label>
                     <item>List with <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Source"/> and <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_TitleLabel"/>.</item>
                  </list>
               </p><lb/>
               <p>The <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.BottomBar"/> contains the following tools.</p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/view-list-details-symbolic.png"/>
                  <head>(Return to) <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_ListView"/></head>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/go-previous.png"/>
                  <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_PreviousAnnotation"/> from the annotation list.</head>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/go-next.png"/>
                  <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_NextAnnotation"/> from the annotation list.</head>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/openAllWindows.png"/>
                  <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_OpenAll"/>: Opens the detailed view of all sources related to the currently selected annotation.</head>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="help/images/closeAllWindows.png"/>
                  <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_CloseAll"/>: Only available if <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_OpenAll"/> was previously run.</head>
               </figure>
            </div>
         </div>
           
          <!-- WORKING WITH ANNOTATIONS -->
           <div type="div1" xml:id="annotations">
              <head>Working with Annotations</head>
              <p>Annotations that come from an edition's Critical Report can be opened in different ways in <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/>.
                 <lb/>(1) Symbols that are already displayed in the source already provide a wide range of information. The complete critical report can also be accessed by double-clicking.
                 <lb/>(2) The complete critical report of an edition is usually available as <ptr type="ediromGui" target="#annotationView"/> under the menu item <term key="view.window.TobBar_View"/> in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.TopBar"/> available. As already mentioned above, some editions also offer an entry into the critical report as a topic in the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.navigator.Navigator"/>.</p>
              <p>Furthermore, <term type="ediromGui" key="global_appName"/> provides the option to create annotations in <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Categories"/> and <term type="ediromGui" key=" view.window.AnnotationView_Priority"/>.
                 The use of these options depends on the edition guidelines (e.g. the categories that were actually used). 
                 Therefore, the following description should not be viewed as a complete documentation, but rather as an introduction to the basic concepts of this consideration.</p>
              <figure>
                 <graphic url="help/images/annotationOverview.png"/>
                 <head>An example screenshot of an annotation icon, showing the tooltip of a single annotation.</head>
              </figure>
              
              <!-- working with annotations PRIORITY -->
              <div type="div2">
                 <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Priority"/></head>
                 <p>A <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Priority"/> gives an indication of the importance of the annotation.
                    The visualization of the <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Priority"/> in the <ptr target="#facsimileView"/> is achieved by color coding the symbols:</p>
                 <figure>
                    <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric1.png"/>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Priority 1</hi> Annotations refer to the edition-specific key issues and are marked red.</p>
                 </figure>
                 <figure>
                    <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric2.png"/>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Priority 2</hi> Annotations refer to important aspects of the edition that are not of the utmost importance for the edition and are marked orange.</p>
                 </figure>
                 <figure>
                    <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric3.png"/>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Priority 3</hi> Annotations contain editorial observations that are normally only of interest to the document sources. These annotations are marked yellow.</p>
                 </figure>
              </div>
              
              <!-- working with annotations CATEGORY -->
              <div type="div2">
                 <head><term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Categories"/></head>
                 <p>Annotations can be associated with one or more <term type="ediromGui" key="view.window.AnnotationView_Categories"/>, each with its own icon. 
                    These symbols are usually also displayed in the color of the coded box in which the annotation symbol is in the <ptr target="#facsimileView"/>.
                    This makes it possible to capture the type or content of the annotation more quickly using the symbol.</p>
                 <p>The available annotation categories depend on the specific edition.
                    Typical examples of annotations are <hi rend="italic">bow placement</hi>, <hi rend="italic">identification of expressions</hi> or <hi rend="italic">articulation</hi>.</p>    
                 <figure>
                    <table rend="frame" xml:id="Table2">
                       <row role="label">
                          <cell>Category</cell>
                          <cell>Symbol in facsimile</cell>
                       </row>
                       <row>
                          <cell>score</cell>
                          <cell>
                             <figure>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotNotation1.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotNotation2.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotNotation3.png"/>
                             </figure>
                          </cell>
                       </row>
                       <row>
                          <cell>Expressive labeling</cell>
                          <cell>
                             <figure>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotExpr1.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotExpr2.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotExpr3.png"/>
                             </figure>
                          </cell>
                       </row>
                       <row>
                          <cell>Choral Text</cell>
                          <cell>
                             <figure>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotText1.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotText2.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotText3.png"/>
                             </figure>
                          </cell>
                       </row>
                       <row>
                          <cell>Combination of different categories</cell>
                          <cell>
                             <figure>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric1.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric2.png"/>
                                <graphic url="help/images/annotGeneric3.png"/>
                             </figure>
                          </cell>
                       </row>
                    </table>
                    <head>Example symbols for categories in annotations.</head>
                 </figure>
              </div>
           </div>
       </body>
   </text>
</TEI>